567 Brownstone Street, Holland, MI me@jacobwestra.com | (616) 312-5302

JACOB B. WESTRA

Objective

I want to use my skills in web development & writing to craft engaging and interactive online experiences. I'm passionate about merging computer science and written media, so I aim to contribute to the ever-changing landscape of digital content, where technology meets storytelling.

Experience

Frontend Web Developer

Dyno Therapeutics, via Open Avenues Foundation August 2023–Present

I'm currently writing an interactive web-article for Massachusetts-based startup Dyno Therapeutics on a recent paper on molecular biology, through the Open Avenues Foundation's micro-internship program.

Science & Technology Reporter

The Calvin University Chimes August 2023–Present

I cover science & technology for Calvin's student newspaper, the Chimes. I've learned a lot about the tech community in Grand Rapids, and made some good connections with a lot of people through interviewing. It's helped me attain the big picture of science & tech.

Web Developer

The Calvin University Chimes December 2023–Present

In-between writing articles for the Chimes, I leveraged my technical skills to redesign their website, Calvinchimes.org. My contributions as a web developer complimented my role as the science/tech writer, allowing me to further bridge the gap between science/tech and readers.

Overnight Camp Counselor

Camp Roger Summer 2023

Worked with kids of all ages, had a lot of fun. It felt great to lead kids both physically and spiritually. It took a lot of energy, but it was more than worth it for the memories made & experiences had. Learned a lot about human behavior, and made connections with a lot of interesting people. It was one of the best summers of my life, and I'd do it all again if I had to.

Student Intern

Yanfeng Automotive Interiors August 2021–February 2022

Worked in finance, dealt with prices for FCA/Stellantis. My work consisted of going into customer databases and correcting/updating prices, comparing them to prices in the Yanfeng database. Had to leave because it was too much to juggle with school work.

Education

Calvin University

Bachelor's in Computer Science Senior, class of 2024

Holland Christian High School

Class of 2020

Extracurricular

Abstraction - Student Organization

Sophomore & junior year, Calvin University

Took on a leadership role in the Calvin computer science student organization, Abstraction. Abstraction was responsible for hosting the 2023 CalvinHacks Hackathon, among other things. I helped organize and lead events, design posters, and manage costs.

Calvin Hackathon

March 2021, 2022, 2023, Calvin University

Worked in a competitive, time-limited environment to make an app with my roommate. In 2023, I helped lead the event.

Holland Christian Robotics Team

7th-12th grade, Holland Christian High School & Middle School

Worked on the design team. Frequently used Solidworks, designed metal and plastic parts. Also was assigned and completed the bill of parts.

References

Nicki Bonczyk

Mentor, Holland Christian Robotics team

Phone | (616) 403-5588

Heather Young

Mentor, Yanfeng Automotive Interiors

Email | hlgradowski@gmail.com

Kelsey Leunk

Camp Director, Camp Roger

Phone | (616) 822-2015